shaklee.com 2019-07-16

# Shaklee Privacy and Security Policy | Shaklee US site

### Overview

Shaklee Corporation ("Shaklee," "we," or "our") recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of information we collect from you. Shaklee Corporation is committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personal information.

This Policy explains how Shaklee Corporation collects, uses, stores, shares, and protects information, including personal information. Shaklee Corporation is committed to collecting, using, storing, sharing, and protecting personal information responsibly. By using Shaklee Corporation's websites, you consent to the collection of personal information. Information that is provided will only be used, stored, and shared for the purposes for which you have consented. This Policy covers both online and offline activities, including information that we collect through our various websites, Distributor events, phone and catalogue orders (among other methods).

By using this website (the "Shaklee Websites") you, the user or distributor as the case may be, ("you") are agreeing to be bound by the current version of the terms of use provided herein.

If we want to change the way we handle your information, we will post those changes in this Privacy Policy. For material changes (i.e., substantially new practices you wouldn't expect from us or that we didn't previously tell you about), we may decide to notify you more prominently and/or give you prior choice. We reserve the right to make changes to our practices and this Policy at any time, provided that we follow the procedures above.

## Shaklee Corporation's collection and use of information

* * *

### What information do we collect?

Depending on how you interact with Shaklee Corporation, we may collect from you various types of information, which are described in more detail below. In some instances (and unless we say otherwise below), we may combine one type of information with another, and store them together in our records. In all cases, however, we strive to limit the amount of information we collect and store to that which is necessary to provide you the relevant services. Shaklee Corporation uses such information for all legal purposes and to provide products and services to you.

**Personal contact information**  
Shaklee Corporation collects personally identifiable information such as your name, mailing address, email, and telephone numbers (home, cell, etc.) entered on Shaklee Corporation's websites or provided directly to Shaklee Corporation. In some cases, this could include information that you give us about someone else (for example, if you ask us to ship a Shaklee product to a friend). We typically collect personal contact information for registration activities, product orders, customer service, contests and promotions, and customer feedback.

**Payment information**  
This includes any information that you use to make a purchase, such as your credit card details (cardholder name, card number, expiration date, etc.), check or other forms of payment (if such are made available). This also includes the billing name and address associated with your form of payment. We only collect payment information for purchases (whether your purchase is made online, by phone, or via catalogue). If you create an account with us, your payment information (along with your order history and other related preferences) may be stored under your account. To review or edit this information, go to the relevant "My Profile" section of our site or contact Customer Service.

**Demographic information**  
This includes any information that describes your demographic. Examples may include your date of birth, age or age range, gender, general geographic location (e.g., zip code or city and state), favorite products, hobbies and interests, income information, or lifestyle information. We typically collect demographic information for registration activities contests and promotions, and customer surveys. For demographic information associated with your profile on a third party social network (e.g., Facebook®), see separate paragraph on "Social network info" below. Demographic information may also be used to personalize your experience on our websites. Aggregate information that cannot identify you may be used and disclosed for general business analysis.

**Technical computer information**  
This includes any information about the computer system or other technological device that you may be using to access one of our websites or applications. We typically collect this information through the use of automated technologies such as cookies and web beacons. Examples of technical computer information may include your computer's IP address, operating system type, and web browser type. If you access a Shaklee website or application via a mobile device such as a smartphone, the collected information may also include your phone's unique device ID, location, and other similar mobile device data. Technical computer information is not typically associated with your personal contact information.

**Website usage information**  
This includes information about how you use and navigate our websites, emails, and applications, including which links you click on, which pages or content you view, and other similar information or statistics about your interactions with a Shaklee site or application (e.g., date and time of visit, which site you came from, etc.). This information is captured using automated technologies such as cookies and web beacons, and may be collected regardless of the device you may be using (computer, smartphone, tablet, etc.). Website usage information may be associated with your personal contact information.

**Customer feedback**  
This includes information that you voluntarily share with us about your experience in using our products and services, including our websites. Examples may include unsolicited comments and suggestions, testimonials, or other feedback about what you may have liked (or disliked) about your experience in using our products or services. We typically collect this information in the form of customer surveys, feedback forms, and email correspondence.

**Customer-generated content**  
This refers to any content that you create and then share with us (and perhaps others) by uploading it to one of our websites, including one of our Facebook pages, other social media pages, or applications. Examples may include photos, videos, personal stories, or other similar media or content. We mostly collect customer-generated content for contests and promotions, website community features, engagement, and third party social networking.

**Social network information**  
This refers to any information that is part of your profile on a third party social network (such as Facebook) and that you allow the third party social network to share with us. Examples may include your basic account information (e.g., name, email address, profile picture, gender, user ID, list of friends, etc.) and any other additional information or activities that you permit the third party social network to share with its application developers. For example, we may receive your social network information (or parts of it) when you download or interact with a Shaklee application on a social networking site (such as Facebook) or use a third party social networking feature that is integrated within a Shaklee site (such as Facebook Connect). To learn more about how your social network information may be obtained by Shaklee (or other application developers), please visit the website of the relevant third party social network.

**Other information (depending on context)**  
This refers to any other information that we might need to collect for the specific Shaklee form, feature, or other service you are using or requesting. What this information might include will vary depending on the method of collection and the specific purpose(s) for which the information is being collected. Please see Section "How do we use your information?" for more specific examples.

* * *

### How do we collect your information?

We may collect information from you through a variety of online or offline sources, which are described in more detail below. In some instances, we may combine information collected from one source (e.g., a Shaklee website) with information collected from another source (e.g., a Shaklee event or party). We do this to get a more complete view of our members and distributors, which, in turn, allows us to serve you better and with more personalization. Also note that not all of the methods listed below may be relevant to you.

**Shaklee websites and applications**  
We may collect information from you through one of our U.S. or international websites or applications. This could include (a) any site that we own and control under our own domain (such as myshaklee.com, Shaklee.com, or some other domain name that redirects you to one of these sites), or (b) any site or web application that we may develop and run on a third party social network such as Facebook. This could also include any site or application that we specifically design for use on a cell phone or other mobile device, such as a mobile-enabled site (i.e., WAP site) or mobile application (e.g., iPad®/iPhone® app). This Policy will only apply if it is posted or linked to on the website or application which you are using.

Please note that some of our non-U.S. websites or applications may post their own privacy policies which are separate from this one. If they post separate policies, those policies will apply instead of this one. Call center and pick-up center orders.

We may collect information from you at an authorized pick-up center or through our call centers, for example if you place an order over the phone.

**Text messaging programs**  
We may collect information from you through one of our inbound text messaging programs. For example, periodically we may allow customers to send us inbound text messages using a short code that we create and advertise in connection with a special offer or promotion. These programs might be advertised at one of our Distributor events or on one of our websites or applications. If you choose to participate in one of these programs, information about your physical location may be collected and used for marketing purposes.

**Email correspondence**  
We may collect information from you if you correspond with us via email. For example, if you send an email to customer service or use our "Email Shaklee" feature, we may obtain certain information about you (such as your contact email address).

**Other sources**  
Occasionally, we may obtain information about you from other sources. For example, we may hire a third-party data aggregator to provide us additional information about our existing customers (this is known as "data appending"). We may also receive information from a third-party co-sponsor whom we may partner with to run a one-time promotion or giveaway.

* * *

### How do we use your information?

The following describes the various purposes and features for which we might collect and use your information, and the different types of information that might be collected for each. Please note, however, that not all of the uses listed below may be relevant to you.

**Order fulfillment**  
We may collect and use your information to process and ship your orders, and to inform you about the status of your orders. Depending on how you make a purchase, this could involve the collection and use of certain personal contact information, payment information, account login information, and/or information related to your purchase (such as products ordered). This could also involve the ongoing storage of your payment information to allow for easier checkout on future purchases.

**Account maintenance**  
We may use your information to maintain your accounts with us (including administering any benefits associated with such accounts). This typically involves the use of any information originally collected to set up your account (e.g., personal contact info, payment info, account login info, demographic info, etc.).

**Provide Member and Distributor services**  
We may collect and use your information to provide you Member and Distributor service, including responses to your inquiries. This typically requires the collection and use of certain personal contact information (such as your name or email address) and information regarding the reason for your inquiry (e.g., order status, technical issue, product question, general question, etc.). This may also include:

  * Creating and managing your accounts
  * Processing Shaklee applications
  * Developing downline genealogy reports

**Personalize product recommendations**  
We may use your information to provide you with Shaklee product recommendations and offers that are tailored to your interests. This mostly involves the use of your previous order history (e.g., from online and/or offline purchases), information provided through Shaklee HealthPrint TM and certain demographic information.

**Website personalization and convenience**  
We may collect and use your information to personalize your experience and save you time when you visit our websites. This is typically done through the use of automated technologies (such as cookies) that collect and remember certain account login information, technical information, and/or previous website usage information. For example, we might remember your login ID or username so you can quickly log in the next time you visit our site or so you can easily retrieve the items you previously placed in your shopping cart. Based on this type of information, we might also show you specific Shaklee content or offers that are more relevant to your interests. We may also use technologies such as our own cookies to provide you with personalized online display advertising. Please see Section "Do we use cookies to gather information?" to disable cookies.

**Contests and promotions**  
We may collect and use your information to administer a contest, sweepstakes, giveaway, competition, or other similar marketing campaign or promotion. These events typically require the collection and use of personal contact information (for prize fulfillment), limited demographic information (for eligibility), and, in some cases, customer-generated content. Due to the customer-generated component, some promotions will be run on third party social networks such as Facebook (e.g., on our Facebook fan page or application). To comply with sweepstakes laws, we may publish or share limited information about the winners of a particular promotion.

**Marketing communications**  
We may collect and use your information to send you marketing communications, such as catalogues, email communications, and SMS text messages. These communications may inform you about new products, events, special discounts, and other news and special offers. Sending you these communications mostly requires the collection and use of certain personal contact information and limited demographic information (such as zip code). In some instances (such as for text messaging programs), this may involve the use of your precise geographical location (obtained from your mobile device) so that we can send you location-based offers. You can always opt out from receiving marketing emails or text messages by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in each such communication. If you have an online account with us, you may be given the option to change your communication preferences under the relevant section of our site or by calling Customer Service. Please note that even if you opt out from receiving marketing communications, you may still receive other communications from us, such as order confirmations, notifications about account activities (e.g., account confirmations, password changes, website etc.), and other important announcements (e.g., product recalls, privacy policy changes, etc.).

**Third party social networking**  
We may collect and use your information so we can allow you to interact with online social networking features provided by third party companies such as Facebook. These tools, some of which are embedded directly into our sites, include features such as "Facebook Connect," "Facebook Share," and "Facebook Like." By offering you these tools, we may be able to (i) obtain certain information about you from your profile on the third party social network (see separate paragraph on "Social network information" **)** and (ii) post to your profile on that social network certain content or activities that you view or interact with on our sites (such as articles, Health Science links, stories, etc.). This exchange of information only occurs when you take some kind of explicit action to permit the sharing (such as clicking on the relevant Facebook feature and creating or logging in to your Facebook account). You can learn more about how these features work by visiting the website of the relevant third party social network.

**Other general purposes (e.g., website security, internal research)**  
We may collect and use your information for other general business purposes, such as to comply with applicable laws and regulatory requirements, to enforce our Terms and Conditions, to maintain the day-to-day operation and security of our websites and applications, and to conduct internal marketing and demographic studies. These activities mostly require the collection and use of certain demographic information, technical computer information, website usage information, and customer feedback.

* * *

### **Do we use cookies to gather information?**

We use cookies on some of our websites. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we put on your device when you visit our website, and which allows us to recognize your computer when you come back to our site at a later time. Cookies allow us to enhance your website experience in several ways. For example, we use cookies to remember the items that you place in your shopping cart and to assess how visitors are using our site. We may also use cookies to personalize certain website features and to show you content and ads more relevant to your interests. By accessing and using our website(s), you consent to our use of cookies.

You can learn more about cookies and how they work at [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).You can always disable cookies through your browser settings. Doing so, however, may disable certain features on our websites, such as online ordering.

To opt out from third party cookies that are used for advertising purposes, you can do so on the NAI website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

* * *

**With whom do we share your information?**  
We may share your information with certain individuals, Shaklee distributors, companies, or in the situations described below. We do not rent or sell your information to third party companies.

**Third party service providers**  
We use third party service providers to help us operate our business or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending emails, fulfilling your product and service requests, mailing products or managing payments. We may share your information with these third parties for limited purposes. These third parties are only allowed to use your information for the specific task they've been hired to do, and for no other purpose. They're also required to keep your information confidential and secure.

**Shaklee Independent Distributors**  
Purchases of Shaklee products through our websites are credited to a Shaklee Independent Distributor, who is available to provide service, information and/or guidance in taking advantage of the benefits of membership in Shaklee. Information you provide to us will also be provided to the Shaklee Independent Distributor to whom your purchase has been assigned in order to facilitate that experience, and may be retained by them as part of their records. If you utilize the Shaklee HealthPrint™ questionnaire, this information would include your individual responses and the related results, as well as the goals you identify. If you do not want us to provide your individual HealthPrint™ responses and results to a Shaklee Independent Distributor, you will have the opportunity to opt out of such disclosure prior to submitting your HealthPrint™.

If you are a Shaklee Independent Distributor, we may disclose certain personal information such as your contact information to customers seeking a Shaklee Independent Distributor or to other Shaklee Independent Distributors such as your upline Business Leader.

**Shaklee Members**  
If you are a Shaklee Member, we may disclose certain personal information such as your contact information to your sponsor or Business Leader of record.

**Business transfer**  
The consent customers have provided herein to the use of their personal information by Shaklee Corporation or its affiliates shall also extend to any person or corporation to which Shaklee Corporation may transfer its business, or in the event of a merger, sale, or assignment of all or a portion of our assets or stock.

**Other disclosures**  
We may disclose your personal information where required or permitted by law or to protect and defend the rights of Shaklee Corporation.

* * *

**How do we protect your information?**  
We use a variety of standard methods (described below) to keep customer information confidential and secure. Please note, however, that these protections do not apply to any information you choose to share in public areas such as our website community features or other social areas.

* * *

**Secure operating environments**  
We store your information in secure operating environments that are protected from the public and that we only allow authorized employees and agents/contractors to access on a need-to-know basis.

* * *

**Encryption for payment info**  
We use industry-standard encryption to provide greater protection for sensitive financial information, such as your credit card information or other payment information, when such information is sent to us over the web. For example, encryption is used when you make payments through our online store, as well as if you choose to have your payment information stored with us for future online purchases.

* * *

**Other security measures**  
In addition to the methods above, we may take other measures to protect your information, depending on the sensitivity of the data and other considerations (such as how the information is collected and where it is stored). These measures may include (among other things) additional access restrictions, password requirements, and physical protections (e.g., secure data centers, etc.).

**Measures you can take**  
It is also important for you to play a role in keeping your information safe. When signing up for an online account, please be sure to choose an account password that is hard for others to guess and never to reveal it to anyone else. If you use a shared or public computer, never choose to have your login ID or password remembered and make sure to log out of your account every time you leave the computer. You should also make use of any privacy features or controls we may provide you in our website community areas.

* * *

**Other important information**  
This section provides additional policy information that is important for you to know or that we may be required to tell you by law

**Your information may be transferred outside your home country**  
Because Shaklee is headquartered in the United States, we may have a need to transfer information collected from our non-U.S. customers and Distributors to the U.S. We may also have a need to transfer our customer and Distributor information (regardless of where you live) to other countries or places in which we or our agents/contractors maintain offices or facilities. By using a Shaklee website or application or by otherwise doing business with Shaklee, you are agreeing to allow us to transfer your information outside your home country and to process it inside the United States or elsewhere for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy.

We do not collect information from children

We do not solicit or collect any type of information from a person known to be under the age of 13. If we discover that we have accidentally collected information from a child, we will remove that information from our records as soon as feasibly possible (or obtain the necessary parental permission to retain it).

* * *

**Public forums**  
Shaklee Corporation makes public forums, such as chat rooms, message boards, Twitter®, or Facebook ("Public Forums"), available to you. Shaklee Corporation asks that you use appropriate caution in disclosing personal information in Public Forums since information disclosed in these areas becomes public information. The privacy provisions herein shall not apply to any personal information submitted via any of the Public Forums.

**We are not responsible for third party sites/features**  
Our websites and applications may provide links to, or features from, other third party sites (such as third party social networks) that we do not own or control. If you click on such links or use such features, you do so at your own risk. We are not responsible for the content or practices of any third party site, application, or feature.

* * *

**Opting out or modifications**  
If you prefer not to receive email messages, text messages or other communications from Shaklee Corporation about new products, promotions or events, you may opt out at any time from receiving such messages by following the "unsubscribe" instructions in such email or text message you received.

If you registered with our website, you will be able to review, modify, update, or remove certain information in your account profile page. Changes may not be effective immediately. We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably possible. However, we may need to retain certain information for record-keeping purposes. We are not responsible for removing information in a third party's database or records (including our Service Providers and Shaklee Independent Distributors) with whom we have already shared your information.

You may also opt out or modify your account information at any time by sending us an email to [fieldsupport@shaklee.com](mailto:fieldsupport@shaklee.com)

* * *

**Updates to this Privacy Policy**  
Shaklee Corporation reserves the right to make changes to this Policy. In the event we make a material change to this Policy, it will be posted here. We encourage you to check this page regularly since your continued use of the Shaklee websites after any changes will be deemed to constitute your acceptance of such changes.

* * *

**Contacting us**  
If you have any questions about this Policy or the practices of this website, you may contact:

Field Support  
Shaklee Corporation  
4747 Willow Road, P-201  
Pleasanton, CA 94588

Questions or comments about Shaklee Corporation can be emailed to  

* * *

Rights granted to Shaklee Corporation for use of any photos or images on this site do not include rights for Shaklee Members, Distributors or Business Leaders to use them. Please do not reuse any images on this site without express written permission from Shaklee Corporation. Thank you.
